# Jorge Andrés Villa Vélez

# **Data Scientist**

20, RUE DE LA PLAINE 75020, PARIS CHEZ GUILLAUD MARIE

07 55 31 30 67 jorgevilla.91@gmail.com Born on the 28th of November 1991 in Medellín, Colombia

Skills

### Soft

Project management, outreach, teaching, written and oral communication, leadership, teamwork

### **Technical**

Data analysis, algorithm development, machine learning

### **Programming**

Python, SQL, IDL, Bash, C (GSL) NumPy, SciPy, Matplotlib, Astropy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Seaborn

# **Data processing**

CIGALE, CASA, Pyraf (IRAF), TOPCAT, DS9, Aladin, Vizier

### Text editing

Microsoft Office, LibreOffice, LaTeX, Kate, Geany

### OS

Linux (Fedora, Ubuntu), Windows, macOS

## Languages

Spanish → Mother tongue

English → Fluent French → Fluent

# Links

#### Website:

https://jurgenvilla.github.io/

### GitHub:

https://github.com/Jurgenvilla

Ph.D. in Astrophysics from Aix-Marseille Université with experience in data analysis of large samples of data (big data) and simulations. I also have experience in project management inside international and European collaborations. I gained experience in the communication of results to large teams. After 3 years of experience in academia, I would like to apply my knowledge and skills in the industry.

# **Professional Experience**

# Laboratoire d'astrophysique de Marseille / Researcher

OCTOBER 2018 - NOVEMBER 2021, MARSEILLE, FRANCE

Analysis of large spectrophotometric samples implementing new models in the bayesian SED fitting code CIGALE. Modification of the code's nebular module.

Models production for the European MOONS (Multi-Object Optical and Near-IR Spectrograph) instrument collaboration, end-2-end simulator, and management in the scientific and technical working groups.

### Universidad de Antioquia / Teacher

JANUARY 2012 - JUNE 2016, MEDELLIN, COLOMBIA

Teaching different courses at the Science faculty such as Astronomy for youngsters, Observational Astronomy and Physics of Waves and Oscillations.

### Universidad Autónoma de México / Research internship

JUNE 2013 - AUGUST 2013, ENSENADA, MEXICO

Internship in observational Astronomy. Collection of data and posterior analysis of observations from the San Pedro Mártir telescopes.

### Education

**Aix-Marseille Université /** Doctor in Astrophysics and Cosmology 2021, MARSEILLE, FRANCE

**Universiteit Leiden** / Master in science Astronomy: Research 2018. LEIDEN. THE NETHERLANDS

Universidad de Antioquia / Bachelor in science: Astronomy

2015, MEDELLIN, COLOMBIA